Register of the Bertram David Wolfe papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Subject File, 1903-1977 (Boxes 54-151)
  - Mandelshtam, Osip (Folder 104: 9)
  - Mao Tse-tung (Folder 104: 10-11)
  - Marcuse, Herbert (Folder 104: 12)
  - Martov, Iulii
    - "Bor'ba Osadnym Polozheniem v Rossiiskoi Sotsialdemokraticheskoi Rabochei Partii: Otvet na Pis'mo N. Lenina'" (The Struggle against the State of Siege in the Russian Social Democratic Labor Party: Reply to a Letter of N. Lenin), 1904 (Folder 104: 13)
      Typed copy. French translation.
    - "Sauveurs ou Destructeurs? Qui Detruisait la R.S.D.R.P. et Comment?" (Saviors or Destroyers? Who Destroyed the R.S.D.R.P. and How?), 1911; Typed copy (Folder 104: 14)
    - "Nakanune Martovskoi Revoliutsii" (On the Eve of the Martov Revolution), undated; Typed copy (Folder 104: 15)
  - Marx, Karl
    - Clippings (Folder 105: 1)
    - Notes (Folder 105: 2-3)
    - Printed matter (Folder 105: 4-6)
    - Writings
      - Kline, George L., "Some Critical Comments on Marx's Philosophy,", 1966; Typescrip (Folder 105: 7)
      - Krieger, Leonard, "The Uses of Marx for History,", undated; Mimeograph (Folder 105: 8)
      - Levine, Norman, "On the Discovery of 'Das Vollendete Geldsystem' and 'Geldwesen, Kreditwesen, Krisen,'", 1975; Typescript (Folder 105: 9)
      - Papaoiannou, Kostas, "Aspects du Marxisme" (Aspects of Marxism), undated; Typescript (Folder 105: 10)
  - Marxian economics (Folder 105: 11)
  - Masani, Minoo R. (Folder 105: 12)
  - Maurin, Joaquin (Folder 105: 13)
  - Meany, George (Folder 106: 1-2)
  - Medicine - U.S. (Folder 106: 3)
  - Medvedev, Zhores (Folder 106: 4)
  - Meherally, Yusuf (Folder 106: 5)
  - Mella, Julio Antonio (Folder 106: 6)
  - Menuhin, Yehudi (Folder 106: 7)
  - Mexican literature (Folder 106: 8)
  - Mexico
    - Civilization (Folder 106: 9)
    - Economic conditions (Folder 106: 10)
    - Historiography - Bailey, David C., "Revisionism in Mexican History (Recent Mexican Historiography): The Revolution,", 1975; Typescript (Folder 106: 11)
    - Politics and government (Folder 106: 12)
    - Social conditions (Folder 106: 13)
  - Mihajlov, Mihajlo (Folder 106: 14)
  - Military service, Compulsory - U.S. (Folder 106: 15)
  - Minorities
    - China (Folder 106: 16)
    - Russia
      - General (Folder 106: 17)
      - General (Folder 107: 1-2)
      - Writings
        - "The Cultural Development of the Nationalities of the Soviet Union,", undated; Typescript (Folder 107: 3)
        - Loewenthal, Rudolf, "The Fate of the Kalmuks and of the Kalmuk ASSR: A Case Study in the Treatment of Minorities in the Soviet Union,", 1952; Mimeograph (Folder 107: 4)
        - "The National Problem in the Soviet Union,", undated; Typescript (Folder 107: 5)
    - U.S. (Folder 107: 6)
  - Miscellany (Folder 107: 7)
  - Modotti, Tina
    - General (Folder 107: 8)
    - Correspondence, 1965-1975 (Folder 107: 9)
  - Molotov, Viacheslav (Folder 107: 10)
  - Mooney, Thomas (Folder 107: 11)
  - Moscow (Folder 107: 12)
  - Music (Folder 107: 13)
  - Narcotic habit
    - General (Folder 107: 14)
    - Correspondence, 1971 (Folder 107: 15)
  - National characteristics, Russian (Folder 107: 16)
  - National socialism (Folder 107: 17)
  - Nationalism (Folder 107: 18-19)
  - Natural law (Folder 108: 1)
  - Natural resources
    - General (Folder 108: 2)
    - Russia (Folder 108: 3)
    - U.S. (Folder 108: 4)
  - Nearing, Scott (Folder 108: 5)
  - Neruda, Pablo (Folder 108: 6)
  - New Leader (Folder 108: 7)
  - New Workers School, New York City (Folder 108: 8-9)
  - New York (City)
    - General (Folder 108: 10)
    - City College (Folder 108: 11)
  - Nikolaevskii, Boris I. (Folder 108: 12)
  - Nixon, Richard M. (Folder 108: 13)
  - Nobel prizes (Folder 108: 14)
  - Nomad, Max (Folder 108: 15)
  - North Atlantic Treaty Organization (Folder 108: 16)
  - Nov'i Zhurnal (Folder 108: 17)
  - Occult sciences - U.S. (Folder 108: 18)
  - Orlov, Alexander
    - General (Folder 109: 1)
    - Correspondence, 1970-1974 (Folder 109: 2)
    - Writings, "Answer to the Questionnaire of Professor S. G. Payne,", 1968; Typescript (Folder 109: 3)
  - Orwell, George (Folder 109: 4)
  - P.E.N. (Folder 109: 5)
  - Panama Canal (Folder 109: 6)
  - Paris - History - Commune (1871) (Folder 109: 7)
  - Partido Obrero de Unificacion Marxista (Folder 109: 8)
  - Partiia Sotsialistov-Revoliutsionerov - Zenzinov, V. M., "Protsess S.R. Moskve v 1922 godu" (The Trial of the S.R., Moscow, 1922), undated (Folder 109: 9)
    Typescript. Includes translation.
  - Passports
    - Russia (Folder 109: 10)
    - U.S. (Folder 109: 11)
  - Pasternak, Boris (Folder 109: 12)
  - People's democracies (Folder 109: 13)
  - Peru - Politics and government (Folder 109: 14)
  - Petersen, William (Folder 109: 15)
  - Philosophy (Folder 109: 16)
  - Philosophy, Russian
    - General (Folder 109: 17)
    - Kamenka, Eugene, "Philosophy in the Soviet Union,", 1963; Mimeograph (Folder 109: 18)
  - Poland - History - 1918-1945 (Folder 110: 1)
  - Police - Russia
    - General (Folder 110: 2-3)
    - Slusser, Robert M., "Chekist Leaders from Dzerzhinsky to Yezhov: Variations on a Theme,", undated; Typescript (Folder 110: 4)
  - Political science (Folder 110: 5-6)
  - Popular fronts (Folder 110: 7)
  - Population (Folder 110: 8)
  - Portugal - Politics and government (Folder 110: 9-10)
  - Pound, Ezra (Folder 111: 1)
  - Problems of Communism (Folder 111: 2)
  - Propaganda, Communist (Folder 111: 3-4)
  - Prophecies
    - General (Folder 111: 5-6)
    - Cohn, Norman, "Monsters of Chaos,", undated; Typescript (Folder 111: 7)
  - Proudhon, Pierre-Joseph (Folder 111: 8)
  - Psychiatric hospitals
    - Russia
      - Clippings (Folder 111: 9)
      - Correspondence, 1971-1973 (Folder 111: 10)
      - Mimeographed material (Folder 111: 11)
      - Notes (Folder 111: 12)
      - Printed matter (Folder 111: 13-14)
    - U.S. - Sosowsky, Larry, "Violence and the Mentally Ill Considered Anew,", 1974; Typescript (Folder 112: 1)
  - Psychology (Folder 112: 2)
  - Public welfare (Folder 112: 3)
  - Publishers and publishing (Folder 112: 4-5)
  - Putnam, Samuel (Folder 112: 6)
  - Race problems
    - General (Folder 112: 7)
    - Rabushka, Alvin, "The Manipulation of Ethnic Politics in Malaya: An Epitaph,", undated; Typescript (Folder 112: 8)
  - Radicalism
    - General (Folder 112: 9)
    - U.S.
      - Clippings (Folder 112: 10-11)
      - Notes (Folder 112: 12)
      - Printed matter (Folder 113: 1)
  - Reed, John (Folder 113: 2)
  - Refugees, Russian (Folder 113: 3)
  - Religion (Folder 113: 4)
  - Revolutions
    - General (Folder 113: 5)
    - Lowenthal, Richard, "Unreason and Revolution: Reflections on the Dissociation of Revolutionary Practice from Marxist Theory,", 1969; Mimeograph (Folder 113: 6)
  - Right and left (political science) (Folder 113: 7)
  - Rivera, Diego
    - General (Folder 113: 8-9)
    - General (Folder 114: 1-4)
    - Clippings (Folder 114: 5-6)
    - Correspondence of Diego Rivera with third parties, 1922-1940 (Folder 114: 7-8)
    - Correspondence of Diego Rivera with third parties, 1922-1940 (Folder 115: 1-3)
    - Correspondence relating to Diego Rivera, 1929-1977 (Folder 115: 4-5)
    - Notebooks (Folder 115: 6-8)
    - Notebooks (Folder 116: 1-4)
    - Portraits, caricatures, etc. (Folder 116: 5)
    - Printed matter (Folder 116: 6-8)
    - Writings
      - Printed copies of writings, 1923-1942 (Folder 117: 1)
      - "A los Obreros y Campesinos de Mexico" (To the Workers and Peasants of Mexico), undated; Holograph (Folder 117: 2)
      - "A los Trabajadores Organizados de Mexico" (To the Organized Workers of Mexico), undated; Holograph and typescript (Folder 117: 3)
      - "Alfaro Siqueiros,", undated; Holograph (Folder 117: 4)
      - "America Debe Descubrir Su Propria Bellez" (America Must Discover Her Own Beauty), 1930; Holograph and typescript (Folder 117: 5)
      - "Con Joaquin Clausell" (With Joaquin Clausell), 1922; Typescript (Folder 117: 6)
      - "Contestacion a los Cargos Concretos Hechos a Diego Rivera ante la Comision de Investigacion que Conoce del Caso de la Escuela Central de Artes Plasticas" (Reply to the Concrete Charges Made against Diego Rivera before the Commission of Investigation that Tries the Case of the Central School of Plastic Arts), undated; Typescript and mimeograph (Folder 117: 7)
      - "En Contra de Diego Rivera? No, en Contra del Joven Arte Plastica Mexicano! En Favor del Sustento" (Against Diego Rivera? No, against the New Mexican Plastic Art! For Support), 1930; Holograph and typescript (Folder 117: 8)
      - "Estado Actual de las Investigaciones Antropoligicas en Mexico y Sugestiones Sobre el Desarrolo Futuro" (Actual State of Anthropological Investigation in Mexico and Suggestions on Its Future Development), undated; Typescript (Folder 117: 9)
      - "Exposicion del Asunto de la Decoracion que se Ejecutura sobre los Muros Centrally Laterales y la Boveda de la Escalera Monumental del Patio del Palacio Nacional" (Exposition on the Subject of the Decoration to be Executed on the Central and Lateral Walls and the Arch of the Monumental Staircase of the Patio of the National Palace), undated; Typescript (Folder 117: 10)
      - "El Fascismo y el Arte" (Fascism and Art), 1935; Typescript (Folder 117: 11)
      - "The Functions of Art,", 1936; Typescript (Folder 117: 12)
      - "H.P.: Sinfonia de Baile" (H.P.: Symphony of Dance), 1931; Typescript (Folder 117: 13)
      - "Mardonio Magana, Campesino, el mas Grande Escultor Mexicano Contemporaneo" (Mardonio Magana, Peasant, the Greatest Contemporary Mexican Sculptor), undated; Holograph and typescript (Folder 117: 14)
      - "Mickey Mouse,", undated; Holograph (Folder 117: 15)
      - "El Nacionalismo y el Arte" (Nationalism and Art), undated; Typescript (Folder 117: 16)
      - "Notas de Discursas sobre el Arte" (Notes on Talks on Art), undated; Holograph (Folder 117: 17)
      - "Painting,", undated; Typescript (Folder 117: 18)
      - "Painting in the New Workers School,", undated; Holograph (Folder 117: 19)
      - "Plan de Estudios para la Escuela Central de Artes Plasticas de Mexico" (Plan of Study for the Central School of Plastic Arts of Mexico), undated; Typescript (Folder 117: 20)
      - "Plan de una Representacion Grafico-Sintetica de la Epoca Antigua de Mexico" (Plan of a Graphic-Synthetic Representation of the Epoch of Antiquity of Mexico), undated; Typescript (Folder 117: 21)
      - "Role of Fresco,", 1932; Typescript (Folder 117: 22)
      - "El Sindicato Revolucionario de Pintores de Mexico y Su Importancia como Factor Revolucionario" (The Revolutionary Union of Painters of Mexico and Its Importance as a Revolutionary Factor), undated; Typescript (Folder 117: 23)
      - "Subject Matter of the Proposed Mural Decorations by Diego Rivera for the Radio Corporation of America Building in the Rockefeller Center, New York City,", undated; Typescript (Folder 117: 24)
      - Untitled, undated; Holographs and typescripts (Folder 117: 25-26)
  - Rivera, Frida Kahlo (Folder 117: 27)
  - Rockfeller family (Folder 117: 28)
  - Ramanov, House of (Folder 117: 29)
  - Romppanen, Klaus (Folder 117: 30)
  - Rosenberg, Julius and Ethel (Folder 118: 1)
  - Rousset, David
    - General (Folder 118: 2)
    - Correspondence, 1949-1959 (Folder 118: 3)
  - Roy, M. N. (Folder 118: 4)
  - Rozek, Edward J. (Folder 118: 5-7)
  - Russell, Bertrand (Folder 118: 8)
  - Russia
    - Armed Forces
      - General (Folder 118: 9-10)
      - Erickson, John, "Soviet Military Performance: Some Manpower and Managerial Constraints,", 1973; Mimeograph (Folder 118: 11)
      - Kenez, Peter, "A Profile of the Prerevolutionary Officer Corps,", undated; Typescript (Folder 118: 12)
      - Kenez, Peter, "Social Mobility in the Russian Officer Corps before the First World War,", undated; Typescript (Folder 118: 13)
    - Civilization (Folder 119: 1)
    - Constitution (Folder 119: 2)
    - Economic conditions
      - 1918-1945 (Folder 119: 3)
      - 1945-1955 (Folder 119: 4-5)
      - 1955-1965 (Folder 119: 6)
      - 1965-1975
        - General (Folder 119: 7-9)
        - Kohler, Foy D., "Soviet Economic Outlook: Political Aspects,", 1973; Typescript (Folder 119: 10)
      - Statistics (Folder 119: 11-12)
    - Economic policy
      - General
        - General (Folder 119: 13)
        - General (Folder 120: 1)
        - Garvy, George, "The Role of the State Bank in Soviet Planning,", 1963; Mimeograph (Folder 120: 2)
      - 1917-1928
        - General (Folder 120: 3)
        - Buchanan, H. Ray, "'War Communism' and the Transition to Socialism: The Supreme Council of the National Economy, 1917-1920,", undated; Typescript (Folder 120: 4)
        - Vol'skii, Nikolai, "Non-Party Specialists and the Coming of the N.E.P.,", undated; Typescript (Folder 120: 5)
      - 1928-1932 (Folder 120: 6)
      - 1938-1942 (Folder 120: 7)
      - 1946-1950 (Folder 120: 8)
      - 1951-1955 (Folder 120: 9)
      - 1956-1958 (Folder 120: 10)
      - 1959-1965
        - General (Folder 120: 11-13)
        - Jasny, Naum, "The Soviet Seven-Year Plan: Is It Realistic?,", 1959; Mimeograph (Folder 120: 14)
      - 1966-1970 (Folder 121: 1-4)
      - 1971-1975 (Folder 121: 5-6)
    - Emigration and immigration (Folder 121: 7)
    - Foreign economic relations (Folder 121: 8)
    - Foreign relations
      - General
        - Clippings (Folder 121: 9)
        - Mimeographed materials (Folder 122: 1)
        - Notes (Folder 122: 2)
        - Printed matter (Folder 122: 3-6)
        - Writings
          - Marantz, Paul, "Stalinist Foreign Policy Doctrine,", undated; Typescript (Folder 122: 7)
          - Rosenthal, Harry Kenneth, "The Soviet Union: Disappointment and Disillusions from a German Standpoint,", undated; Typescript (Folder 122: 8)
      - Africa (Folder 122: 9)
      - Arab countries (Folder 122: 10)
      - Asia (Folder 122: 11)
      - Austria (Folder 122: 12)
      - China
        - Clippings (Folder 123: 1)
        - Notes (Folder 123: 2)
        - Printed matter (Folder 123: 3-5)
        - Writings
          - Jaffe, Philip J., "The Sino-Soviet Dispute: Highlights of Its History, Prospects for Its Future,", undated; Mimeograph (Folder 123: 6)
          - Jaffe, Philip J., "Sino-Soviet Relations,", undated; Typescript (Folder 123: 7)
      - Europe, Eastern (Folder 123: 8-9)
      - Finland (Folder 123: 10)
      - Germany (Folder 124: 1-3)
      - Great Britain (Folder 124: 4)
      - India (Folder 124: 5)
      - Israel (Folder 124: 6)
      - Japan (Folder 124: 7)
      - Norway (Folder 124: 8)
    - Historiography
      - Clippings (Folder 124: 9)
      - Mimeographed material (Folder 124: 10)
      - Notes (Folder 124: 11)
      - Printed matter (Folder 124: 12-13)
      - Printed matter (Folder 125: 1-2)
      - Writings, Solski, Waclaw, "The Soviet Bible,", undated; Typescript (Folder 125: 3)
    - History
      - General
        - General (Folder 125: 4-6)
        - Notebooks (Folder 125: 7-8)
        - Notebooks (Folder 126: 1-2)
        - Pictorial works (Folder 126: 3)
      - Revolution (March-November 1917)
        - Clippings (Folder 126: 4-5)
        - Mimeographed material (Folder 126: 6)
        - Notes (Folder 126: 7-8)
        - Printed matter (Folder 127: 1-6)
        - Writings, Rabinowitch, Alexander, comment on Robert V. Daniels, "Bolshevik Preparations for October,", 1967; Typescript (Folder 127: 7)
      - Revolution (1917-1921)
        - General
          - General (Folder 127: 8)
          - General (Folder 128: 1-2)
          - Schapiro, Leonard, letter to the editor, Times Literary Supplement, 1958; Typescript (Folder 128: 3)
        - Counter-revolutionary movements (Folder 128: 4)
      - Allied intervention (1918-1920)
        - General (Folder 128: 5)
        - Wolin, Simon, "American Intervention in Siberia in 1918-1920,", undated; Typescript (Folder 128: 6)
    - Politics and government
      - General (Folder 128: 7)
      - Writings
        - Schwartz, Joel J. and William R. Keech, "Group Influence over the Policy Process in the Soviet Union,", undated; Mimeograph (Folder 128: 8)
        - Theen, Rolf H. W., "Political Science in the USSR: 'To Be or Not To Be': Some Reflections on the Implications of a Recent Soviet Critique of American Political Science,", 1970; Mimeograph (Folder 128: 9)
    - Population (Folder 128: 10)
    - Social conditions
      - General (Folder 128: 11-12)
      - Farnsworth, Beatrice, "Bolshevik Alternatives and the Soviet Family: The 1926 Marriage Law Debate,", 1975; Typescript (Folder 128: 13)
  - Russian literature (Folder 128: 14-15)
  - Russo-German Treaty (1939) (Folder 129: 1)
  - Sacco, Nicola and Bartolomeo Vanzetti (Folder 129: 2)
  - Saint-Simon, Henri de (Folder 129: 3)
  - Sakharov, Andrei (Folder 129: 4)
  - Sartre, Jean-Paul (Folder 129: 5)
  - Schapiro, Leonard (Folder 129: 6)
  - Schlesinger, Arthur M., Jr. (Folder 129: 7)
  - Schwarz, Solomon
    - General (Folder 129: 8)
    - Correspondence, 1952-1954 (Folder 129: 9)
  - Science
    - General (Folder 129: 10)
    - Russia
      - General (Folder 129: 11-12)
      - Writings
        - Epstein, Paul S., "The Diamat and the Point of View of Modern Science,", undated; Mimeograph (Folder 130: 1)
        - London, Ivan D., "Russian Psychology and Psychiatry,", 1951; Mimeograph (Folder 130: 2)
        - "Usloviia Nauchnoi Raboty v SSSR v Oblasti Biologii" (Conditions of Research in Soviet Biology), 1952; Mimeograph (Folder 130: 3)
  - Scott, John (Folder 130: 4)
  - Sedova, Natalia (Folder 130: 5)
  - Serge, Victor
    - General (Folder 130: 6)
    - Correspondence, 1941 (Folder 130: 7)
  - Shatov, William (Folder 130: 8)
  - Shockley, William B. (Folder 130: 9-10)
  - Sholokhov, Mikhail (Folder 130: 11)
  - Shostakovich, Dmitri (Folder 130: 12)
  - Silone, Ignazio (Folder 130: 13)
  - Sinclair, Upton (Folder 130: 14)
  - Siniavskii, Andrei (Folder 130: 15)
  - Siqueiros, David Alfaro
    - General (Folder 130: 16)
    - Correspondence, 1973-1976 (Folder 130: 17)
  - Smal-Stocki, Roman (Folder 130: 18)
  - Social classes
    - General (Folder 130: 19)
    - Russia (Folder 130: 20)
  - Socialism
    - General
      - General (Folder 131: 1)
      - Herberg, Will, "Socialism and Freedom,", 1944; Typescript (Folder 131: 2)
    - Africa (Folder 131: 3)
    - Asia (Folder 131: 4)
    - France (Folder 131: 5)
    - Germany (Folder 131: 6)
    - Great Britain (Folder 131: 7)
    - Russia
      - Clippings (Folder 131: 8)
      - Notes (Folder 131: 9)
      - Printed matter (Folder 131: 10-12)
      - Writings, Frankel, Jonathan, "Russian Jewish Socialism in the Era of Emigration and Revolution,", 1973; Mimeograph (Folder 132: 1)
    - Sweden (Folder 132: 2)
    - U.S. (Folder 132: 3-4)
  - Socialist International (Folder 132: 5)
  - Solzhenitsyn, Aleksandr
    - Clippings (Folder 132: 6-8)
    - Mimeographed material (Folder 132: 9)
    - Notes (Folder 132: 10)
    - Printed matter (Folder 133: 1-3)
  - Sorel, Georges - Roth, Jack J., "Georges Sorel: On Lenin and the Bolshevik Revolution,", 1975; Typescript (Folder 133: 4)
  - South Africa - Race question (Folder 133: 5)
  - Souvarine, Boris (Folder 133: 6-7)
  - Spain
    - Civilization (Folder 133: 8)
    - History - Civil War (1936-1939)
      - General
        - Clippings (Folder 133: 9-10)
        - Correspondence - Wolfe, Ella, 1937 (Folder 133: 11)
        - Notes (Folder 133: 12)
        - Printed matter (Folder 134: 1-2)
      - Refugees (Folder 134: 3)
    - Politics and government (Folder 134: 4-5)
  - Spencer, Herbert (Folder 134: 6)
  - Sperber, Manes (Folder 134: 7)
  - Sports - Communist countries (Folder 134: 8)
  - Stalin, Iosif
    - Clippings (Folder 134: 9-11)
    - Mimeographed material (Folder 135: 1)
    - Notes (Folder 135: 2-3)
    - Portraits, caricatures, etc. (Folder 135: 4)
    - Printed matter (Folder 135: 5-8)
    - Quotations (Folder 136: 1)
    - Writings
      - Levine, Isaac Don, Stalin Was a Tsarist Agent, undated; Mimeograph (Folder 136: 2)
      - Lockhart, Sir Robert Bruce, "Stalin and the Bolshevik Revolution,", undated; Mimeograph (Folder 136: 3)
      - Stalin, Iosif, letter to the editor, New Leader, 1926; Mimeograph (Folder 136: 4)
      - Weinreich, Uriel, "The Significance of the Soviet Linguistic Controversy,", 1952; Typescript (Folder 136: 5)
  - Stanford University (Folder 136: 6)
  - Stanford-for-Czechoslovakia Committee (Folder 136: 7)
  - Stankevich, Vladimir (Folder 136: 8)
  - Strong, Anna Louise (Folder 136: 9)
  - Student movements
    - General (Folder 136: 10)
    - U.S.
      - Clippings (Folder 136: 11-12)
      - Notes (Folder 136: 13)
      - Printed matter (Folder 137: 1)
  - Sverdlov, Iakob - Duval, Charles, "Jacob Sverdlov: The Irreplaceable Bolshevik,", undated; Typescript (Folder 137: 2)
  - Taiwan
    - General (Folder 137: 3)
    - Wu, Yuan-li, statement before U.S. House of Representatives, Foreign Affairs Committee, Subcommittee on Asian and Pacific Affairs, 1971; Mimeograph (Folder 137: 4)
  - Tarsis, Valeriy (Folder 137: 5)
  - Taxation - U.S.
    - General (Folder 137: 6)
    - Smith, Dan Throop, statement before U.S. House of Representatives, Committee on Ways and Means, 1973; Typescript (Folder 137: 7)
  - Technology (Folder 137: 8-9)
  - Teller, Edward (Folder 137: 10)
  - Thalheimer, August, An Introduction to Dialectical Materialism, 1935 (Folder 137: 11)
    Correspondence.
  - Thomas, Norman (Folder 137: 12)
  - Togliatti, Palmiro (Folder 137: 13)
  - Totalitarian ethics (Folder 137: 14)
  - Totalitarianism
    - Clippings (Folder 138: 1)
    - Notes (Folder 138: 2-3)
    - Printed matter (Folder 138: 4-6)
    - Quotations, maxims, etc. (Folder 138: 7-9)
  - Trade-unions
    - General (Folder 139: 1)
    - U.S.
      - Clippings (Folder 139: 2-3)
      - Printed matter (Folder 139: 4-6)
  - Traven, B. (Folder 139: 7)
  - Tresca, Carlo
    - General (Folder 139: 8)
    - "Autobiography,", undated; Typescript (Folder 139: 9)
  - Trotskii, Lev
    - Clippings (Folder 140: 1)
    - Notes (Folder 140: 2)
    - Portraits, caricatures, etc. (Folder 140: 3)
    - Printed matter (Folder 140: 4-6)
    - Quotations (Folder 140: 7)
    - Writings
      - "Deuxieme Siezde du Parti Ouvrier Social-Democrate de Russie" (Second Congress of the Russian Social Democratic Labor Party), 1903; Typed copy (Folder 140: 8)
      - Interview with Henriette Celarie, 1938; Typed copy (Folder 140: 9)
      - "K Voprosu o Perspektivakh Mirovogo Razvitiia" (On the Perspectives of World Development), translation, 1924; Typed copy (Folder 140: 10)
      - "Trotsky,", undated; Typescript (Folder 140: 11)
      - Ziv, G. A., "Trotskii,", undated; Typed copy (Folder 140: 12)
  - Truman, Harry S. (Folder 140: 13)
  - Tsereteli, Irakli (Folder 140: 14)
  - Tsvetaeva, Marina (Folder 140: 15)
  - Underground literature - Russia
    - General (Folder 141: 1-2)
    - Boiter, Albert, "Samizdat: Primary Source Material in the Study of Current Soviet Affairs,", 1972; Typescript (Folder 141: 3)
  - United Nations (Folder 141: 4-5)
  - United Nations Educational, Scientific and Cultural Organization (Folder 141: 6)
  - U.S.
    - Armed Forces (Folder 141: 7)
    - Centennial celebrations, etc.
      - Clippings (Folder 141: 8)
      - Notes (Folder 141: 9-10)
      - Printed matter (Folder 142: 1)
    - Central Intelligence Agency (Folder 142: 2)
    - Civilization (Folder 142: 3)
    - Commerce - Russia (Folder 142: 4-5)
    - Diplomatic and consular service (Folder 142: 6)
    - Economic conditions
      - General (Folder 142: 7-8)
      - Discourse in Depression, Typescript (Folder 143: 1)
    - Federal Bureau of Investigation (Folder 143: 2)
    - Foreign opinion, Russian (Folder 143: 3)
    - Foreign relations
      - General
        - General (Folder 143: 4-5)
        - Emmet, Christopher, "Primer of American Policy in the Cold War,", 1954; Mimeograph (Folder 143: 6)